Guide to the Margaret H. Laidlaw Richardson Papers, 1916-1928
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Margaret H. Laidlaw Richardson Papers
1916-1928
Richardson, Margaret H. Laidlaw, 1900-1998
0.4 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
A collection of papers created by Margaret H. Laidlaw Richardson (VC 1923) during her time at Vassar College, including a photograph album; Vassar College exams, syllabi, and grades; and College Entrance Exam exams and scores.
Biographical Note
Margaret Hamilton Laidlaw (1900-1998) was born in New York City to doctor George Frederick Laidlaw and his wife Laura Kissam Laidlaw. She attended the Veltin School For Girls in Manhattan between 1915 and 1919 before attending Vassar. While at Vassar, Laidlaw studied English and met friends Elizabeth R. Brownell (VC 1923) and Harvia (Wilson) Russell (VC 1923), as well as her future husband, Avery G. Richardson of Bayside, NY. After graduation, she taught French at a girls' school in Texas and married Richardson in 1924.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains a photograph album of Margaret H. Laidlaw Richardson's (VC 1923) time at Vassar College; Vassar College exams, syllabi, and grades; College Entrance Exam exams and scores; and other ephemera gathered by Laidlaw during her time at Vassar.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Student Materials Collection
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Education
Document Types:
Examinations (documents); Photograph albums; Syllabi
VCL Categories:
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, June 2023.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Kristen M. Richardson, May 2023.
Container List
- Clippings, 1921-1928 (Folder 1)
- College Entrance Examination Board, receipts and number assignments, 1918-1919 (Folder 2)
- College Entrance Exams - English, 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
- College Entrance Exams - French, 1918, 1920 (Folder 4)
- College Entrance Exams - History A, "Ancient History", 1919 (Folder 5)
- College Entrance Exams - Latin, 1916-1919 (Folder 6)
- College Entrance Exams - Mathematics, 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
- College Entrance Exams - Physics, 1919 (Folder 8)
- Italy American Society, telegram clipping, circa 1920 (Folder 9)
- Photograph Album, 1919-1923 (Folder 10)
- Vassar College Alumnae House guest cards, undated (Folder 11)
- Vassar College class schedule, undated (Folder 12)
- Vassar College Committee on Admission, exam scores, 1918 Jul-Sep (Folder 13)
- Vassar College Exams - French 7, 1920 Jan (Folder 14)
- Vassar College Exams - Latin, 1920 Jan (Folder 15)
- Vassar College Exams - Mathematics, "Plane Trigonometry", 1920 Jan 23 (Folder 16)
- Vassar College Exams - Philosophy 12, "Ethics", 1922 Jun (Folder 17)
- Vassar College Exams - Physics 3, 1920 (Folder 18)
- Vassar College Exams - Zoology 12, 1922 Jun 2 (Folder 19)
- Vassar College report cards, 1919-1923 (Folder 20)
- Vassar College Syllabus - "Introduction to Philosophy", 1918 (Folder 21)